Oliver Otis Howard Papers M091 M091
George J. Mitchell Department of Special Collections & Archives, Bowdoin College Library, Brunswick, Maine 04011
- M91.6: Correspondence, retirement, December 1894-1912, undated, M91.6; 8.5 linear feet
  - 1899 Mar 08 - 1899 Mar 11 (Box 35, Folder 24)
  - 1899 Mar 12 - 1899 Mar 15 (Box 35, Folder 25)
  - 1899 Mar 16 - 1899 Mar 19 (Box 35, Folder 26)
  - 1899 Mar 20 - 1899 Mar 23 (Box 35, Folder 27)
  - 1899 Mar 24 - 1899 Mar 27 (Box 35, Folder 28)
  - 1899 Mar 28 - 1899 Mar 31 (Box 35, Folder 29)
  - 1899 Apr 01 - 1899 Apr 04 (Box 35, Folder 30)
  - 1899 Apr 05 - 1899 Apr 07 (Box 35, Folder 31)
  - 1899 Apr 08 - 1899 Apr 14 (Box 35, Folder 32)
  - 1899 Apr 15 - 1899 Apr 30 (Box 35, Folder 33)
  - 1899 May 01 - 1899 May 10 (Box 35, Folder 34)
  - 1899 May 11 - 1899 May 19 (Box 35, Folder 35)
  - 1899 May 20 - 1899 May 25 (Box 35, Folder 36)
  - 1899 May 26 - 1899 May 29 (Box 35, Folder 37)
  - 1899 May 30 - 1899 May 31 (Box 35, Folder 38)
  - 1899 Jun 01 - 1899 Jun 02 (Box 35, Folder 39)
  - 1899 Jun 03 - 1899 Jun 08 (Box 35, Folder 40)
  - 1899 Jun 09 - 1899 Jun 12 (Box 35, Folder 41)
  - 1899 Jun 13 - 1899 Jun 15 (Box 35, Folder 42)
  - 1899 Jun 16 - 1899 Jun 19 (Box 35, Folder 43)
  - 1899 Jun 20 - 1899 Jun 23 (Box 35, Folder 44)
  - 1899 Jun 24 - 1899 Jun 28 (Box 35, Folder 45)
  - 1899 Jun 28 (Box 35, Folder 46)
  - 1899 Jun 29 - 1899 Jun 30 (Box 35, Folder 47)
  - 1899 Jul 01 - 1899 Jul 07 (Box 35, Folder 48)
  - 1899 Jul 08 - 1899 Jul 09 (Box 35, Folder 49)
  - 1899 Jul 10 - 1899 Jul 12 (Box 35, Folder 50)
  - 1899 Jul 13 - 1899 Jul 17 (Box 35, Folder 51)
  - 1899 Jul 18 - 1899 Jul 19 (Box 35, Folder 52)
  - 1899 Jul 20 - 1899 Jul 24 (Box 35, Folder 53)
  - 1899 Jul 25 - 1899 Jul 31 (Box 35, Folder 54)
  - 1899 Aug 01 - 1899 Aug 05 (Box 35, Folder 55)
  - 1899 Aug 06 - 1899 Aug 10 (Box 35, Folder 56)
  - 1899 Aug 11 - 1899 Aug 15 (Box 35, Folder 57)
  - 1899 Aug 16 - 1899 Aug 20 (Box 35, Folder 58)
  - 1899 Aug 21 - 1899 Aug 25 (Box 35, Folder 59)
  - 1899 Aug 26 - 1899 Aug 31 (Box 35, Folder 60)
  - 1899 Sep 01 - 1899 Sep 06 (Box 35, Folder 61)
  - 1899 Sep 07 - 1899 Sep 11 (Box 35, Folder 62)
  - 1899 Sep 12 - 1899 Sep 13 (Box 35, Folder 63)
  - 1899 Sep 14 - 1899 Sep 18 (Box 35, Folder 64)
  - 1899 Sep 19 - 1899 Sep 23 (Box 35, Folder 65)
  - 1899 Sep 24 - 1899 Sep 28 (Box 35, Folder 66)
  - 1899 Sep 29 - 1899 Sep 30 (Box 35, Folder 67)
  - 1899 Oct 01 - 1899 Oct 07 (Box 35, Folder 68)
  - 1899 Oct 08 - 1899 Oct 11 (Box 35, Folder 69)
  - 1899 Oct 12 - 1899 Oct 13 (Box 35, Folder 70)
  - 1899 Oct 14 - 1899 Oct 20 (Box 35, Folder 71)
  - 1899 Oct 21 - 1899 Oct 31 (Box 35, Folder 72)
  - 1899 Nov 01 - 1899 Nov 05 (Box 35, Folder 73)
  - 1899 Nov 06 - 1899 Nov 10 (Box 35, Folder 74)
  - 1899 Nov 11 - 1899 Nov 22 (Box 35, Folder 75)
  - 1899 Nov 23 - 1899 Nov 30 (Box 35, Folder 76)
  - 1899 Dec 01 - 1899 Dec 05 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - 1899 Dec 06 - 1899 Dec 10 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - 1899 Dec 11 - 1899 Dec 13 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - 1899 Dec 14 - 1899 Dec 18 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - 1899 Dec 19 - 1899 Dec 22 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - 1899 Dec 23 - 1899 Dec 26 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - 1899 Dec 27 - 1899 Dec 28 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - 1899 Dec 29 - 1899 Dec 31 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - 1900 Jan 01 - 1900 Jan 05 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - 1900 Jan 06 - 1900 Jan 10 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - 1900 Jan 11 - 1900 Jan 16 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - 1900 Jan 17 - 1900 Jan 22 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - 1900 Jan 23 - 1900 Jan 26 (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - 1900 Jan 27 - 1900 Jan 31 (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - 1900 Feb 01 - 1900 Feb 07 (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - 1900 Feb 08 - 1900 Feb 09 (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - 1900 Feb 10 - 1900 Feb 13 (Box 36, Folder 17)
  - 1900 Feb 14 - 1900 Feb 18 (Box 36, Folder 18)
  - 1900 Feb 19 - 1900 Feb 23 (Box 36, Folder 19)
  - 1900 Feb 24 - 1900 Feb 28 (Box 36, Folder 20)
  - 1900 Mar 01 - 1900 Mar 04 (Box 36, Folder 21)
  - 1900 Mar 05 - 1900 Mar 07 (Box 36, Folder 22)
  - 1900 Mar 08 - 1900 Mar 10 (Box 36, Folder 23)
  - 1900 Mar 11 - 1900 Mar 14 (Box 36, Folder 24)
  - 1900 Mar 15 - 1900 Mar 17 (Box 36, Folder 25)
  - 1900 Mar 18 - 1900 Mar 22 (Box 36, Folder 26)
  - 1900 Mar 23 - 1900 Mar 28 (Box 36, Folder 27)
  - 1900 Mar 29 - 1900 Mar 31 (Box 36, Folder 28)
  - 1900 Apr 01 - 1900 Apr 05 (Box 36, Folder 29)
  - 1900 Apr 06 - 1900 Apr 09 (Box 36, Folder 30)
  - 1900 Apr 10 - 1900 Apr 15 (Box 36, Folder 31)
  - 1900 Apr 16 - 1900 Apr 20 (Box 36, Folder 32)
  - 1900 Apr 22 - 1900 Apr 25 (Box 36, Folder 33)
  - 1900 Apr 26 - 1900 Apr 30 (Box 36, Folder 34)
  - 1900 May 01 - 1900 May 07 (Box 36, Folder 35)
  - 1900 May 08 - 1900 May 18 (Box 36, Folder 36)
  - 1900 May 19 - 1900 May 28 (Box 36, Folder 37)
  - 1900 May 29 - 1900 May 31 (Box 36, Folder 38)
  - 1900 Jun 01 - 1900 Jun 07 (Box 36, Folder 39)
  - 1900 Jun 08 - 1900 Jun 11 (Box 36, Folder 40)
  - 1900 Jun 12 - 1900 Jun 18 (Box 36, Folder 41)
  - 1900 Jun 19 - 1900 Jun 23 (Box 36, Folder 42)
  - 1900 Jun 24 - 1900 Jun 30 (Box 36, Folder 43)
  - 1900 Jul 01 - 1900 Jul 06 (Box 36, Folder 44)
  - 1900 Jul 07 - 1900 Jul 12 (Box 36, Folder 45)
  - 1900 Jul 13 - 1900 Jul 18 (Box 36, Folder 46)
  - 1900 Jul 19 - 1900 Jul 23 (Box 36, Folder 47)
  - 1900 Jul 24 - 1900 Jul 31 (Box 36, Folder 48)
  - 1900 Aug 01 - 1900 Aug 11 (Box 36, Folder 49)
  - 1900 Aug 12 - 1900 Aug 20 (Box 36, Folder 50)
  - 1900 Aug 21 - 1900 Aug 31 (Box 36, Folder 51)
  - 1900 Sep 01 - 1900 Sep 12 (Box 36, Folder 52)
  - 1900 Sep 13 - 1900 Sep 19 (Box 36, Folder 53)
  - 1900 Sep 20 - 1900 Sep 30 (Box 36, Folder 54)
  - 1900 Oct 01 - 1900 Oct 19 (Box 36, Folder 55)
  - 1900 Oct 20 - 1900 Oct 31 (Box 36, Folder 56)
  - 1900 Nov 01 - 1900 Nov 05 (Box 36, Folder 57)
  - 1900 Nov 06 - 1900 Nov 09 (Box 36, Folder 58)
  - 1900 Nov 10 - 1900 Nov 14 (Box 36, Folder 59)
  - 1900 Nov 15 - 1900 Nov 19 (Box 36, Folder 60)
  - 1900 Nov 20 - 1900 Nov 23 (Box 36, Folder 61)
  - 1899 Nov 24 - 1900 Nov 27 (Box 36, Folder 62)
  - 1900 Nov 28 - 1900 Nov 30 (Box 36, Folder 63)
  - 1900 Dec 01 - 1900 Dec 03 (Box 36, Folder 64)
  - 1900 Dec 04 - 1900 Dec 07 (Box 36, Folder 65)
  - 1900 Dec 08 - 1900 Dec 12 (Box 36, Folder 66)
  - 1900 Dec 13 - 1900 Dec 17 (Box 36, Folder 67)
  - 1900 Dec 18 - 1900 Dec 24 (Box 36, Folder 68)
  - 1900 Dec 25 - 1900 Dec 31 (Box 36, Folder 69)
  - 1901 Jan 01 - 1901 Jan 06 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - 1901 Jan 07 - 1901 Jan 08 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - 1901 Jan 09 - 1901 Jan 14 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - 1901 Jan 15 - 1901 Jan 18 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - 1901 Jan 19 - 1901 Jan 22 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - 1901 Jan 23 - 1901 Jan 25 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - 1901 Jan 26 - 1901 Jan 29 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - 1901 Jan 30 - 1901 Jan 31 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - 1901 Feb 01 - 1901 Feb 03 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - 1901 Feb 04 - 1901 Feb 05 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - 1901 Feb 06 - 1901 Feb 08 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - 1901 Feb 09 - 1901 Feb 10 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - 1901 Feb 11 - 1901 Feb 13 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - 1901 Feb 14 - 1901 Feb 17 (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - 1901 Feb 18 - 1901 Feb 19 (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - 1901 Feb 20 - 1901 Feb 22 (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - 1901 Feb 23 - 1901 Feb 26 (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - 1901 Feb 27 - 1901 Feb 28 (Box 37, Folder 18)
  - 1901 Mar 01 - 1901 Mar 03 (Box 37, Folder 19)
  - 1901 Mar 04 - 1901 Mar 08 (Box 37, Folder 20)
  - 1901 Mar 09 - 1901 Mar 12 (Box 37, Folder 21)
  - 1901 Mar 13 - 1901 Mar 15 (Box 37, Folder 22)
  - 1901 Mar 16 - 1901 Mar 17 (Box 37, Folder 23)
  - 1901 Mar 18 - 1901 Mar 19 (Box 37, Folder 24)
  - 1901 Mar 20 - 1901 Mar 21 (Box 37, Folder 25)
  - 1901 Mar 22 - 1901 Mar 25 (Box 37, Folder 26)
  - 1901 Mar 26 - 1901 Mar 27 (Box 37, Folder 27)
  - 1901 Mar 28 - 1901 Mar 31 (Box 37, Folder 28)
  - 1901 Apr 01 - 1901 Apr 03 (Box 37, Folder 29)
  - 1901 Apr 04 - 1901 Apr 07 (Box 37, Folder 30)
  - 1901 Apr 08 - 1901 Apr 11 (Box 37, Folder 31)
  - 1901 Apr 12 - 1901 Apr 14 (Box 37, Folder 32)
  - 1901 Apr 15 - 1901 Apr 16 (Box 37, Folder 33)
  - 1901 Apr 17 - 1901 Apr 20 (Box 37, Folder 34)
  - 1901 Apr 21 - 1901 Apr 24 (Box 37, Folder 35)
  - 1901 Apr 25 - 1901 Apr 28 (Box 37, Folder 36)
  - 1901 Apr 29 - 1901 Apr 30 (Box 37, Folder 37)
  - 1901 May 01 - 1901 May 03 (Box 37, Folder 38)
  - 1901 May 04 - 1901 May 10 (Box 37, Folder 39)
  - 1901 May 11 - 1901 May 15 (Box 37, Folder 40)
  - 1901 May 16 - 1901 May 20 (Box 37, Folder 41)
  - 1901 May 21 - 1901 May 27 (Box 37, Folder 42)
  - 1901 May 28 - 1901 May 31 (Box 37, Folder 43)
  - 1901 Jun 01 - 1901 Jun 05 (Box 37, Folder 44)
  - 1901 Jun 06 - 1901 Jun 09 (Box 37, Folder 45)
  - 1901 Jun 10 - 1901 Jun 12 (Box 37, Folder 46)
  - 1901 Jun 13 - 1901 Jun 20 (Box 37, Folder 47)
  - 1901 Jun 21 - 1901 Jun 30 (Box 37, Folder 48)
  - 1901 Jul 01 - 1901 Jul 05 (Box 37, Folder 49)
  - 1901 Jul 06 - 1901 Jul 14 (Box 37, Folder 50)
  - 1901 Jul 15 - 1901 Jul 19 (Box 37, Folder 51)
  - 1901 Jul 20 - 1901 Jul 24 (Box 37, Folder 52)
  - 1901 Jul 25 - 1901 Jul 31 (Box 37, Folder 53)
  - 1901 Aug 01 - 1901 Aug 05 (Box 37, Folder 54)
  - 1901 Aug 06 - 1901 Aug 14 (Box 37, Folder 55)
  - 1901 Aug 15 - 1901 Aug 31 (Box 37, Folder 56)
  - 1901 Sep 01 - 1901 Sep 09 (Box 37, Folder 57)
  - 1901 Sep 10 - 1901 Sep 19 (Box 37, Folder 58)
  - 1901 Sep 20 - 1901 Sep 30 (Box 37, Folder 59)
  - 1901 Oct (Box 37, Folder 60)
  - 1901 Nov 01 - 1901 Nov 10 (Box 37, Folder 61)
  - 1901 Nov 11 - 1901 Nov 30 (Box 37, Folder 62)
  - 1901 Dec 01 - 1901 Dec 07 (Box 37, Folder 63)
  - 1901 Dec 08 - 1901 Dec 14 (Box 37, Folder 64)
  - 1901 Dec 15 - 1901 Dec 20 (Box 37, Folder 65)
  - 1901 Dec 21 - 1901 Dec 26 (Box 37, Folder 66)
  - 1901 Dec 27 - 1901 Dec 31 (Box 37, Folder 67)
  - 1902 Jan 01 - 1902 Jan 04 (Box 37, Folder 68)
  - 1902 Jan 05 - 1902 Jan 09 (Box 37, Folder 69)
  - 1902 Jan 10 - 1902 Jan 16 (Box 37, Folder 70)
  - 1902 Jan 17 - 1902 Jan 19 (Box 37, Folder 71)
  - 1902 Jan 20 - 1902 Jan 22 (Box 37, Folder 72)
  - 1902 Jan 23 - 1902 Jan 27 (Box 37, Folder 73)
  - 1902 Jan 28 - 1902 Jan 29 (Box 37, Folder 74)
  - 1902 Jan 30 - 1902 Jan 31 (Box 37, Folder 75)
  - 1902 Feb 01 - 1902 Feb 04 (Box 37, Folder 76)
  - 1902 Feb 05 - 1902 Feb 07 (Box 37, Folder 77)
  - 1902 Feb 08 - 1902 Feb 12 (Box 37, Folder 78)
  - 1902 Feb 13 - 1902 Feb 18 (Box 37, Folder 79)
  - 1902 Feb 19 - 1902 Feb 22 (Box 37, Folder 80)
  - 1902 Feb 23 - 1902 Feb 25 (Box 37, Folder 81)
  - 1902 Feb 26 - 1902 Feb 28 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - 1902 Mar 01 - 1902 Mar 04 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - 1902 Mar 05 - 1902 Mar 06 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - 1902 Mar 07 - 1902 Mar 11 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - 1902 Mar 12 - 1902 Mar 17 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - 1902 Mar 18 - 1902 Mar 27 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - 1902 Mar 28 - 1902 Mar 31 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - 1902 Apr 01 - 1902 Apr 08 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - 1902 Apr 09 - 1902 Apr 20 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - 1902 Apr 21 - 1902 Apr 27 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - 1902 Apr 28 - 1902 Apr 30 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - 1902 May 01 - 1902 May 09 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - 1902 May 10 - 1902 May 19 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - 1902 May 20 - 1902 May 31 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - 1902 Jun 01 - 1902 Jun 13 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - 1902 Jun 14 - 1902 Jun 23 (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - 1902 Jun 24 - 1902 Jun 30 (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - 1902 Jul 01 - 1902 Jul 11 (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - 1902 Jul 12 - 1902 Jul 18 (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - 1902 Jul 19 - 1902 Jul 31 (Box 38, Folder 20)
  - 1902 Aug 01 - 1902 Aug 06 (Box 38, Folder 21)
  - 1902 Aug 07 - 1902 Aug 14 (Box 38, Folder 22)
  - 1902 Aug 15 - 1902 Aug 25 (Box 38, Folder 23)
  - 1902 Aug 26 - 1902 Aug 31 (Box 38, Folder 24)
  - 1902 Sep 01 - 1902 Sep 10 (Box 38, Folder 25)
  - 1902 Sep 12 - 1902 Sep 19 (Box 38, Folder 26)
  - 1902 Sep 20 - 1902 Sep 30 (Box 38, Folder 27)
  - 1902 Oct (Box 38, Folder 28)
  - 1902 Nov (Box 38, Folder 29)
  - 1902 Dec (Box 38, Folder 30)
  - 1903 Jan - 1903 Apr (Box 38, Folder 31)
  - 1903 May - 1903 Aug (Box 38, Folder 32)
  - 1903 Sep - 1903 Dec (Box 38, Folder 33)
  - 1904 Jan - 1904 Feb (Box 38, Folder 34)
  - 1904 Feb - 1904 Jun (Box 38, Folder 35)
  - 1904 Jul - 1904 Dec (Box 38, Folder 36)
  - 1905 (Box 38, Folder 37)
  - 1906 Jan - 1906 Jun (Box 38, Folder 38)
  - 1906 Jul - 1906 Dec (Box 38, Folder 39)
  - 1907 Jan - 1907 May (Box 38, Folder 40)
  - 1907 Jun - 1907 Aug (Box 38, Folder 41)
  - 1907 Sep - 1907 Nov (Box 38, Folder 42)
  - 1907 Dec (Box 38, Folder 43)
  - 1908 Jan - 1908 Feb (Box 38, Folder 44)
  - 1908 Mar - 1908 May (Box 38, Folder 45)
  - 1908 Jun - 1908 Dec (Box 38, Folder 46)
  - 1909 - 1912 (Box 38, Folder 47)
  - [undated] (Box 38, Folder 48)
- M91.7: Correspondence (bound), 1861-1905, M91.7; 7.75 linear feet
  Scribe's copy-books and letterpress volumes containing copies of Howard's outgoing correspondence from 1864 through 1905, complementing the collection's other correspondence series (M91.1-M91.6). The volumes cover all aspects of his career. Because of the fragile condition of the originals, microfilms of the letterpress correspondence are available. Each volume, including one containing his aide-de-camp's letters, have indexes to the correspondents. There is some overlap between the later copy-books and the early letterpress volumes; errors can be found in the copy-books.
  Reproduction note:
  This series is available online. Microfilm of letterpress volumes are available.
  - 1861 - 1865, Also contains daily action reports; telegraphic messages; orders and circulars; telegraphic messages; orders and circulars; telegrams received; endorsements and memoranda; etc. (Volume-folio 1)
  - 1864 Feb - 1866 Oct (copybook) (Volume-folio 2)
  - 1866 Nov - 1867 Nov (copybook) (Volume-folio 3)
  - 1867 Nov - 1869 Jun (copybook) (Volume-folio 4)
  - [1868 May - 1872 Jul] (Aide-de-Camp book) (Volume-folio 5)
  - 1869 Jun - 1871 May (copybook) (Volume-folio 6)
  - 1871 May - 1873 Mar (copybook) (Volume-folio 7)
  - 1873 Mar 7 - Dec 16 (copybook) (Volume-folio 8)
  - 1866 Nov 20 - 1867 Jun 20 (Volume-folio 9)
  - 1867 Jun 21 - Dec 30 (Volume-folio 10)
  - 1868 Jan 4 - Jul 15 (cover lists last date as July 5, 1868) (Volume-folio 11)
  - 1868 Jul 16 - 1869 Apr 16 (Volume-folio 12)
  - 1869 Apr 4 - Dec 23 (Volume-folio 13)
  - 1869 Dec 29 - 1870 Aug 4 (Volume-folio 14)
  - 1870 Aug 4 - 1871 May 1 (Volume-folio 15)
  - 1871 May 1 - Nov 3 (Volume-folio 16)
  - 1871 Nov 3 - 1872 Dec 11 (Volume-folio 17)
  - 1872 Dec 13 - 1873 Mar 24 (Volume-folio 18)
  - 1873 Mar 24 - Nov 9 (Volume-folio 19)
  - 1873 Nov 3 - 1874 Jul 28 (Volume-folio 20)
  - 1874 Sep 4 - 1876 May 12 (Volume-folio 21)
  - 1876 May 15 - 1877 Dec 11 (Volume 22)
  - 1877 Dec 11 - 1878 Nov 23 (Volume 23)
  - 1878 Nov 25 - 1879 Nov 22 (Volume 24)
  - 1879 Nov 13 - 1880 Nov 23 (Volume 25)
  - 1881 Jan 29 - May 27 (Volume-folio 26)
  - 1881 May 27 - Oct 13 (Volume 27)
  - 1881 Oct 17 - 1882 Mar 20 (Volume-folio 28)
  - 1882 Mar 15 - Nov 7 (Volume-folio 29)
  - 1882 Nov 7 - 1883 Apr 27 (Volume-folio 30)
  - 1883 Apr 28 - 1884 Nov 24 (Volume-folio 31)
  - 1884 Nov 24 - 1885 Jun 2 (Volume-folio 32)
  - 1885 Jun 3 - 1886 Jan 4 (Volume-folio 33)
  - 1886 Jan 4 - Apr 8 (Volume-folio 34)
  - 1886 Apr 9 - Nov 4 (Volume-folio 35)
  - 1886 May 28 - 1888 Mar 12 (Volume-folio 36)
  - 1886 Sep 27 - 1888 Nov 20 (Volume-folio 37)
  - 1888 Mar 13 - Nov 22 (Volume-folio 38)
  - 1888 Dec 12 - 1889 Feb 7 (Volume-folio 39)
  - 1889 Feb 8 - Aug 15 (Volume-folio 40)
  - 1889 Aug 15 - Jan 30 (Volume-folio 41)
  - 1890 Jan 30 - Jun 14 (Volume-folio 42)
  - 1890 Jun 17 - Dec 8 (Volume-folio 43)
  - 1890 Dec 8 - 1891 Apr 16 (Volume-folio 44)
  - 1891 Apr 16 - Oct 10 (Volume-folio 45)
  - 1891 Oct 12 - 1892 Feb 8 (Volume-folio 46)
  - 1892 Feb 8 - Jul 23 (Volume-folio 47)
  - 1892 Jul 25 - Dec 19 (Volume-folio 48)
  - 1892 Dec 19 - 1893 May 16 (Volume-folio 49)
  - 1893 May 17 - Dec 8 (Volume-folio 50)
  - 1893 Dec 9 - 1894 May 16 (Volume-folio 51)
  - 1894 May 16 - 1894 Oct 2 (Volume-folio 52)
  - 1894 Nov 2 - 1895 May 6 (Volume-folio 53)
  - 1895 May 4 - 1897 Apr 5 (Volume-folio 54)
  - 1897 Apr 6 - 1900 Aug 25 (Volume-folio 55)
  - 1900 Aug 25 - 1905 Dec 6 (Volume-folio 56)
- M91.8: Articles and addresses, bound volumes and scrapbooks, 1863-1866, undated, M91.8; 5.25 linear feet
  Articles and addresses by Howard, manuscript, typescript. Most, though once bound, are now loose though their volumes designation is preserved, others (mostly containing clippings and designated "Miscellaneous") are still in their bound state. An incomplete index is available (M91.9) for use in Special Collections. The indexes and rough subject groupings were prepared by Howard or his staff. Loose: v.1, "Biographical"; v.2, "Wars and Campaigns"; v.3, "Indians" and "Military"; v.4 and 5 (numbered consecutively with v.5 starting at no. 31), "Religion and Miscellaneous"; v.6, "Civil War" and "Children's Stories"; v.7, "Miscellaneous" to v.11 are largely made up of unrelated items covering the Civil War, religion, the military, history, Native Americans, biographical subjects, education, politics, etc. Bound: roughly divided by subject, including the Civil War, Indian campaigns, personal reminiscences and miscellaneous. Volume 11 is followed by unnumbered series. (See the container list for a volume by volume breakdown.)
  Arranged numerically by volume.
  - Articles and Addresses Civil War (Volume-folio 1)
  - Indian Campaigns - letterpress copybook (Volume-folio 2)
  - Nez Perce - letterpress copybook (Volume-folio 3)
  - Miscellaneous (Volume-folio 4)
  - Miscellaneous - Oct. 23, 1893 to (Volume-folio 5)
  - Miscellaneous - letterpress copybook (Volume-folio 6)
  - Scrapbooks (clippings). 1863 - 1866 (Vol. 1) (Volume-folio 7)
  - Scrapbooks (clippings). Miscellaneous (Vol. 2) (Volume-folio 8)
  - Scrapbooks (clippings). Miscellaneous (Vol. 3) (Volume-folio 9)
  - Scrapbooks (clippings). Miscellaneous (Vol. 4) (Volume-folio 10)
  - Scrapbooks (clippings). Religious lectures, notices, etc. (Volume-folio 11)
  - Scrapbooks (clippings). Personal reminiscences of the War of the Rebellion (Volume-folio 12)
  - Scrapbooks (clippings). [Writings for children] (Volume-folio 13)
  - Scrapbooks (clippings). Nez Perce (Volume-folio 14)
  - Scrapbooks (clippings). [Indians] (Volume-folio 15)
  - Scrapbooks (clippings). Articles on the Indians, Gold and Silver Question - 1896 (Volume-folio 16)
  - Scrapbooks (clippings). Miscellaneous (Volume-folio 17)
  - Scrapbooks (clippings). Miscellaneous (Volume 18)
  - Scrapbooks (clippings). Miscellaneous (Volume-folio 19)
  - Scrapbooks (clippings). Miscellaneous (Volume-folio 20)
  - Scrapbooks (clippings). Miscellaneous (Volume 21)
  - Scrapbooks (clippings). Miscellaneous (Volume 22)
  - Table of Contents (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Biographical (Vol. 1). Sherman, W.T., and his corps commanders (No. 1) (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Biographical (Vol. 1). Butler, Benjamin F. (No. 2) (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Biographical (Vol. 1). Crooks, George (No. 3) (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Biographical (Vol. 1). Grant, Ulysses S., At Chattanooga (No. 4) (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Biographical (Vol. 1). Grant, Ulysses S. (No. 5) (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Biographical (Vol. 1). Grant, Ulysses S., Comparison of Washington and Grant (No. 6) (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Biographical (Vol. 1). Hale, Nathan (No. 7) (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Biographical (Vol. 1). Hancock, Winfield S. and Howard, O.O. (No. 8) (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Biographical (Vol. 1). Jackson, Andrew (No. 9) (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Biographical (Vol. 1). Lee, S. Perry (No. 10) (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Biographical (Vol. 1). McDowell, Irvin and Thomas, George H. (No. 11) (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Biographical (Vol. 1). Sheridan, Philip (No. 12) (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Biographical (Vol. 1). Sherman, W.T. - Characteristics of youth (No. 13) (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Biographical (Vol. 1). Sherman, W.T.-Intro to "Life of Sherman" by Hubbard (No. 14) (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Biographical (Vol. 1). Sherman, W.T. (No. 15) (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Biographical (Vol. 1). Sherman, W.T. (No. 16) (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - Biographical (Vol. 1). Slocum, Henry W. - Eulogy (No. 17) (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - Biographical (Vol. 1). Thomas, George H. (No. 19B) (Box 39, Folder 19)
  - Wars and Campaigns (Vol. 2). Adairsville - Georgia Campaign of 1864 (No. 1) (Box 39, Folder 20)
  - Wars and Campaigns (Vol. 2). Chattanooga and Atlanta (100 days campaign) (No.2) (Box 39, Folder 21)
  - Wars and Campaigns (Vol. 2). "Atlanta is ours and fairly won" (No.3) (Box 39, Folder 22)
  - Wars and Campaigns (Vol. 2). Sherman's advance from Atlanta (No. 4) (Box 39, Folder 23)
  - Wars and Campaigns (Vol. 2). "The Struggle for Atlanta" (No. 5) (Box 39, Folder 24)
  - Wars and Campaigns (Vol. 2). "Through to Atlanta" (No. 6) (Box 39, Folder 25)
  - Wars and Campaigns (Vol. 2). "Federal Rout at Bull run" (No. 7) (Box 39, Folder 26)
  - Wars and Campaigns (Vol. 2). "Sherman's Campaign through the Carolinas and Savannah" (No. 8) (Box 39, Folder 27)
  - Wars and Campaigns (Vol. 2). "Jackson's Attack on the Right at Chancellorsville" (No. 9) (Box 39, Folder 28)
  - Wars and Campaigns (Vol. 2). "The Georgia Campaign of 1864" (No. 10) (Box 39, Folder 29)
  - Wars and Campaigns (Vol. 2). "Campaign and Battle of Gettysburg" (No. 11) (Box 39, Folder 30)
  - Wars and Campaigns (Vol. 2). "Campaign of Gettysburg" (No. 11 1/2) (Box 39, Folder 31)
  - Wars and Campaigns (Vol. 2). "Grant at Vicksburg" (No. 12) (Box 39, Folder 32)
  - Wars and Campaigns (Vol. 2). "Jackson's Campaigns" (No. 13) (Box 39, Folder 33)
  - Wars and Campaigns (Vol. 2). "Jackson's Campaigns" (No. 14) (Box 39, Folder 34)
  - Wars and Campaigns (Vol. 2). "Resaca and the Oostanaula" (No. 15) (Box 39, Folder 35)
  - Wars and Campaigns (Vol. 2). "From the Potomac to the Tennessee" (No. 16) (Box 39, Folder 36)
  - Wars and Campaigns (Vol. 2). "Resaca" - 2 copies (No. 17) (Box 39, Folder 37)
  - Wars and Campaigns (Vol. 2). "The Revolutionary War - 2 copies (No. 18) (Box 39, Folder 38)
  - Wars and Campaigns (Vol. 2). "Vicksburg" (No. 19) (Box 39, Folder 39)
  - Wars and Campaigns (Vol. 2). "The War of 1812" (No. 20) (Box 39, Folder 40)
  - Indians (Vol. 3). "The Story of Antonio Azul, a Pima Indian" (No. 1) (Box 39, Folder 41)
  - Indians (Vol. 3). "An Indian Battle" (Nez Perce) (No. 2) (Box 39, Folder 42)
  - Indians (Vol. 3). "The Instincts of Indian Children" - (No. 3) [2 copies] (Box 39, Folder 43)
  - Indians (Vol. 3). "Indian Attack on Dabney House near Union now Arcata, Cal." (No. 4) [2 copies] (Box 39, Folder 44)
  - Indians (Vol. 3). "Department of Columbia" (No. 5) (Box 39, Folder 45)
  - Indians (Vol. 3). "Our Indians of the Southwest - First Paper" (No. 6) (Box 39, Folder 46)
  - Indians (Vol. 3). "Our Indians of the Southwest - Second Paper" (No. 7) (Box 39, Folder 47)
  - Indians (Vol. 3). "Our Indians of the Southwest - Third Paper" (No. 8) (Box 39, Folder 48)
  - Indians (Vol. 3). "What now shall be done with the Indians" (No. 9) (Box 39, Folder 49)
  - Indians (Vol. 3). "Mattie Leigh's Correspondence" (No. 10) (Box 39, Folder 50)
  - Indians (Vol. 3). "Mission Indians of Southern California" (No. 11) (Box 39, Folder 51)
  - Indians (Vol. 3). "Piute and Bannock Indian Wars" (No. 12) [2 copies] (Box 39, Folder 52)
  - Indians (Vol. 3). "The Sioux Indian Wars" (No. 13)[2 copies] (Box 39, Folder 53)
  - Indians (Vol. 3). "Squaw Men" (No. 14) (Box 39, Folder 54)
  - Military (Vol. 3). "The Army" (No. 15) (Box 39, Folder 55)
  - Military (Vol. 3). "The Army"-(No. 17) (Box 39, Folder 56)
  - Military (Vol. 3). "Take care of the Army and the Navy" (No. 18) (Box 39, Folder 57)
  - Military (Vol. 3). "The Army Past and Present" (No. 19) (Box 39, Folder 58)
  - Military (Vol. 3). "Classmates whose lives were surrendered during this Rebellion" (No. 20) (Box 39, Folder 59)
  - Military (Vol. 3). "Floating Batteries" (No. 21) (Box 39, Folder 60)
  - Military (Vol. 3). "Some fallen heroes of Gettysburg" (No. 22) (Box 39, Folder 61)
  - Military (Vol. 3). "The Grand Review of Washington" (No. 23) (Box 39, Folder 62)